Firas Kudsy



firaskudsy@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/firaskudsy



6472058090



https://github.com/firaskudsy

Summary

A full-stack application developer with a passion for building great web applications, with over 20 years of proven Software Development skills and proficiency in the latest programming languages and frameworks technologies gained through years of successful implementations through Agile Methodologies. Capable of carrying tasks independently or with minimal supervision. Solutions orientated, performing very well under pressure, achieving deadlines and working within budgets.

Experience



Senior full stack developer

Nov 2018 - Present (3 years 3 months +)

- Technical Architecture Design for multiple QE custom tools.
- Develop and Maintain various reporting web applications for Coverage, ROI, test executions, accessibility code, and environment downtime. The stack includes (MS SQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, NestJs, React.js, Angular, Nginx)
- Develop and Maintain various backend Rest API, services, and microservices to integrate HP ALM, Jira, JTMF with QE Custom tools.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades.
- Lead web application migration to production on Azure.



Full Stack Developer

Fitviser.com

Dec 2016 - Nov 2018 (2 years)

- Create innovative, interactive, and Scalable E-Commerce web applications. The stack includes (Firebase, MongoDB, NodeJS, Loopback, Angular, Nginx, and Jenkins)
- Develop and Maintain User Dashboard Web Applications.
- Develop and Maintain Hybrid E-Commerce Mobile Dashboard.
- Take part in the technical architecture design process.



Full Stack Developer

Freelance Web Development

Jan 2015 - Jul 2016 (1 year 7 months)

- Developed a Hybrid Mobile Apps for Restaurant Ordering, Delivery and tracking using ionic framework, AngularJS and Nodejs
- · Developed a scheduling web application using Angular2 and Firebase to manage employees tasks and resources

Software Developer

AL ITKAN (Siemens agent)

Jun 2009 - Dec 2014 (5 years 7 months)

- Developed a collaborative applications using VB.NET, SQL Server and DevExpress including HR, Stock management, travel Visa system and custom salary management
- Designed and Built wordpress sites with modern responsive web UI standards
- Analyzed business needs and planned methods to improve business process and performance using custom designed software
- Debugged and Resolved bugs in .NET applications to ensure optimal development environment
- Designed data structures and stored procedures, and tune existing stored procedures on SQL Server 2008

Software Developer

AFAC - The Arab Fund for Arts and Culture

Jun 2007 - May 2009 (2 years)

- Developed a Contacts dashboard system Microsoft Sharepoint
- Built a Custom data migration tool to collect and export filtered data to be imported later into a SharePoint Server
- Designed and Developed multiple business website using wordpress, HTML, Css, JavaScript and MySQL

Software Developer

AL ITKAN Communication (Siemens agent)

Aug 2004 - May 2007 (2 years 10 months)

- Developed a full Helpdesk application using VB.NET, SQL Server and Crystal report to manage service request, available technician, time schedules and resources
- Developed a Call centre application using VB.NET, SQL Server and Crystal report to record incoming clients request, claims and confirmation.

Education



Baghdad University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 1993 - 1998

Computer Scince

Skills

Node.js • Web Development • React.js • Angular • MongoDB • NestJS • JavaScript • Firebase REST APIs
Nginx